<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Leadership on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/tags/leadership/</link><description>Recent content in Leadership on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/tags/leadership/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leading Across Cultures: Navigating Cross-Cultural Leadership Challenges in Indonesia</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/cultural-case-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/cultural-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Raj, an British national with ten years of experience in ABC&amp;rsquo;s Indian branch, was promoted to Managing Director of the company&amp;rsquo;s Indonesian subsidiary, he expected his leadership transition to be smooth. However, within months, he faced difficulties promoting local managers internally. Few employees applied for senior positions, and those who did often withdrew before interviews.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leading Through Transition: Evaluating Engineering Transformation in a Scaling Organization</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XYZ is a tech company that offers services through an online platform where contractors can upload their legal documents. The enterprise is transitioning from a small start-up to an SME, reporting double-digit growth over the past six years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leadership Under Extreme Conditions: A Human Resource Analysis of Ernest Shackleton's Expedition</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/shackleton-leadership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/shackleton-leadership/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1911, the Norwegian explorer Amundsen won the race to the South Pole, beating the British Scott, who died in the attempt. It was a massive setback for the British, who had dominated the exploration world until then. In an effort to restore their reputation, Sir Ernest Shackleton embarked, alongside 27 other crew members, on the so-called &amp;ldquo;Imperial Trans-Antarctica Expedition&amp;rdquo; (ITAE) in 1915, hoping to cross Antarctica from sea to sea. At the dawn of World War I, this ill-fated expedition put an end to the great era of polar exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reframing Culture and Collaboration: Microsoft's Transformation Under Satya Nadella</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-paced industries such as technology, change is an ongoing necessity. Market dynamics evolve rapidly, innovation cycles shorten, and emerging competitors continuously redefine industry standards. In this environment, organizations must adapt faster than the technologies they create. Microsoft, once a dominant force in personal computing, found itself constrained by internal silos, outdated hierarchies, and a culture that incentivized competition over collaboration. As the industry shifted toward cloud computing and artificial intelligence, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s traditional model no longer aligned with market realities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>