<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Breaking the Credit Barrier: Structural Challenges of SME Financing in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="issue"&gt;Issue&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kiwi SMEs, representing 99% of the total businesses and 35% of the country&amp;rsquo;s GDP (MBIE, 2017), do not have access to the same lending conditions as the residential mortgage market. This briefing will provide insights into the implications of tight lending conditions for SMEs - with up to 50 employees - and recommendations on how to improve the situation.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Incentives, Externalities, and Unintended Consequences: France’s Long Dependence on Diesel</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After WWII, Charles de Gaulle jump-started the French economy by cutting diesel taxes for the first time, supporting haulers, farmers, and artisans who relied on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in 1980, Toyota and its revolutionary production model flooded the French market with economical and reliable cars. At the same time, France replaced all its diesel-based power plants with nuclear ones to ensure energy independence. The French government also introduced new diesel incentives to boost the competitive advantage of local manufacturers specializing in diesel engines and to dispose of the million litres of now-useless diesel from power plants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>