<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Research on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/</link><description>Recent content in Research on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leading Across Cultures: Navigating Cross-Cultural Leadership Challenges in Indonesia</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/cultural-case-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Aug 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/cultural-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When Raj, an British national with ten years of experience in ABC&amp;rsquo;s Indian branch, was promoted to Managing Director of the company&amp;rsquo;s Indonesian subsidiary, he expected his leadership transition to be smooth. However, within months, he faced difficulties promoting local managers internally. Few employees applied for senior positions, and those who did often withdrew before interviews.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Breaking the Credit Barrier: Structural Challenges of SME Financing in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) form the backbone of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s economy, representing 99% of all businesses and contributing approximately 35% of national GDP (MBIE, 2017). Despite their importance, SMEs face disproportionately tight lending conditions compared to the residential mortgage market. Restricted access to affordable credit limits their ability to invest, expand, and sustain growth, especially for firms employing fewer than 50 people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Winning on Simplicity: Aldi's Dual Strategy of Cost Leadership and Quality Differentiation</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/aldi-strategic-case-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/aldi-strategic-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Aldi blazed the trail for the hard-discounters within the US grocery retail industry. The firm&amp;rsquo;s current obsession with product quality, combined with its focus on low prices (Ramaswamy, 2020), suggests that winning for the company means offering &lt;strong&gt;the best quality at the lowest price&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leading Through Transition: Evaluating Engineering Transformation in a Scaling Organization</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XYZ is a tech company that offers services through an online platform where contractors can upload their legal documents. The enterprise is transitioning from a small start-up to an SME, reporting double-digit growth over the past six years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Purpose Meets Profit: Insights from Emerging Social Entrepreneurs in Toronto</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social entrepreneurship has emerged as a distinctive response to complex social and environmental challenges that traditional business and public institutions have failed to address effectively. By combining entrepreneurial methods with social purpose, these ventures aim to create value that extends beyond financial profit. Yet, despite growing academic and policy interest, the lived experiences of social entrepreneurs, and the factors that shape their motivations, behaviours, and constraints, remain insufficiently understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Retail to the Cloud: Strategic Reinvention and Competitive Advantage at Amazon</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/amazon-strategic-case-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/amazon-strategic-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon&amp;rsquo;s evolution from an online bookstore into a global technology ecosystem represents one of the most remarkable strategic transformations in modern business history. Founded in 1994 by Jeff Bezos, the company has expanded across e-commerce, logistics, entertainment, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence. Today, it dominates multiple industries simultaneously, driven by a culture of innovation, customer obsession, and data-centric decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Operational Excellence in High-Growth Environments: A Case Study on Scaling Without Losing Value</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/opex-during-scale-up/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/opex-during-scale-up/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XYZ is transitioning from a small tech start-up to a larger organization, reporting double-digit growth over the past six years. Today, the company is experiencing difficulties in satisfying its customers&amp;rsquo; needs. This briefing aims to provide the company with recommendations on how to keep delivering value during its ongoing scale-up phase.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Balancing Profit and Preservation: Sustainable Strategies for Wildlife Management in South Africa</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kruger National Park is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most biodiverse conservation areas, renowned for its ecological management practices and anti-poaching operations. It attracts millions of visitors each year, contributing significantly to South Africa&amp;rsquo;s tourism economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unpacking the Housing Affordability Crisis: Structural Drivers and Policy Pathways in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1990, successive housing booms have pushed New Zealand property prices to levels increasingly out of reach for many aspiring first-time buyers. While existing homeowners have benefited from rising equity, newcomers face a market where the cost of ownership absorbs a disproportionate share of household income. In economic terms, this violates the equimarginal principle, which states that rational agents allocate their limited resources across different needs to maximize overall satisfaction. When housing consumes nearly all disposable income, individuals can no longer balance spending efficiently across other essential goods and services, making homeownership economically unsustainable for many Kiwis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Incentives, Externalities, and Unintended Consequences: France's Long Dependence on Diesel</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After WWII, Charles de Gaulle jump-started the French economy by cutting diesel taxes for the first time, supporting haulers, farmers, and artisans who relied on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in 1980, Toyota and its revolutionary production model flooded the French market with economical and reliable cars. At the same time, France replaced all its diesel-based power plants with nuclear ones to ensure energy independence. The French government then introduced new diesel incentives to boost the competitive advantage of local manufacturers specializing in diesel engines and to dispose of the million litres of now-useless diesel from power plants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leadership Under Extreme Conditions: A Human Resource Analysis of Ernest Shackleton's Expedition</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/shackleton-leadership/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/shackleton-leadership/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In 1911, Norwegian explorer Roald Amundsen reached the South Pole ahead of Britain&amp;rsquo;s Robert Falcon Scott, who died in the attempt. It was a massive setback for the British, who had dominated the exploration world up to that point. Eager to restore their reputation, Sir Ernest Shackleton launched the &lt;em&gt;Imperial Trans-Antarctic Expedition&lt;/em&gt; (ITAE) in 1914 with 27 other crew members, aiming to cross the continent from sea to sea. At the dawn of World War I, this ill-fated expedition marked the end of the great era of polar exploration.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reframing Culture and Collaboration: Microsoft's Transformation Under Satya Nadella</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-paced industries such as technology, change is an ongoing necessity. Market dynamics evolve rapidly, innovation cycles shorten, and emerging competitors continuously redefine industry standards. In this environment, organizations must adapt faster than the technologies they create. Microsoft, once a dominant force in personal computing, found itself constrained by internal silos, outdated hierarchies, and a culture that incentivized competition over collaboration. As the industry shifted toward cloud computing and artificial intelligence, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s traditional model no longer aligned with market realities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>