<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economics &amp; Finance on Nadia Zablah Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/topics/economics-finance/</link><description>Recent content in Economics &amp; Finance on Nadia Zablah Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/topics/economics-finance/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Finance Fundamentals for Tech Leaders</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/finance-fundamentals/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/finance-fundamentals/</guid><description/></item><item><title>How Purpose Create Economic Resilience</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/04/17/purpose-economic-resilience/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Apr 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/04/17/purpose-economic-resilience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Periods of crisis often expose the limits of efficiency-based economics. While lean operations and financial optimization maximize short-term performance, they leave systems vulnerable to disruption. The past decade has shown that stability depends as much on capital and technology as on &lt;em&gt;trust, coherence, and shared purpose&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Rethinking Productivity and Innovation in Mature Economies</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/01/10/productivity-paradox/</link><pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/01/10/productivity-paradox/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Despite unprecedented technological progress, productivity growth in advanced economies has slowed over the past decades. This paradox (known as the &lt;em&gt;Solow Paradox&lt;/em&gt;) reveals a structural disconnect between innovation potential and realized economic output. Digitalization, automation, and data abundance might have transformed industries, but they have not produced proportional gains in efficiency or prosperity.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Price of Stability: How Policy Distorts Market Incentives</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2024/05/18/price-of-stability/</link><pubDate>Sat, 18 May 2024 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2024/05/18/price-of-stability/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Economic stability is typically framed as an unquestionable public good. Governments design fiscal, monetary, and regulatory mechanisms to mitigate volatility, protect employment, and preserve consumer confidence. Yet stability, when pursued indiscriminately, can produce the very fragilities it aims to prevent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Breaking the Credit Barrier: Structural Challenges of SME Financing in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Small and medium-sized enterprises (SMEs) form the backbone of New Zealand&amp;rsquo;s economy, representing 99% of all businesses and contributing approximately 35% of national GDP (MBIE, 2017). Despite their importance, SMEs face disproportionately tight lending conditions compared to the residential mortgage market. Restricted access to affordable credit limits their ability to invest, expand, and sustain growth, especially for firms employing fewer than 50 people.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Unpacking the Housing Affordability Crisis: Structural Drivers and Policy Pathways in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1990, successive housing booms have pushed New Zealand property prices to levels increasingly out of reach for many aspiring first-time buyers. While existing homeowners have benefited from rising equity, newcomers face a market where the cost of ownership absorbs a disproportionate share of household income. In economic terms, this violates the equimarginal principle, which holds that rational agents allocate their limited resources across competing needs to maximize overall utility and satisfaction. When housing consumes nearly all disposable income, individuals can no longer balance spending efficiently across other essential goods and services, making homeownership economically unsustainable for many Kiwis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Incentives, Externalities, and Unintended Consequences: France's Long Dependence on Diesel</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After the Second World War, Charles de Gaulle jump-started the French economy by lowering diesel taxes for the first time, providing targeted support to haulers, farmers, and artisans who relied heavily on diesel fuel.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>