<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Strategic Management on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/topics/strategic-management/</link><description>Recent content in Strategic Management on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/topics/strategic-management/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Balanced Scorecard: Translating Strategy into Measurable Performance</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/balanced-scorecard/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/balanced-scorecard/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Developed in the early 1990s, the &lt;em&gt;Balanced Scorecard (BSC)&lt;/em&gt; revolutionized how organizations translate strategy into action. While traditional performance systems focused almost exclusively on financial results, the Balanced Scorecard integrates &lt;strong&gt;financial and non-financial perspectives&lt;/strong&gt;, linking day-to-day activities with long-term strategic objectives.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Power–Interest Matrix: Mapping Stakeholders for Strategic Alignment</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/power-interest-matrix/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/power-interest-matrix/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every strategic initiative depends on people: those who influence it, those who enable it, and those who are affected by it. The &lt;em&gt;Power–Interest Matrix&lt;/em&gt; provides a simple framework for identifying, analyzing, and managing stakeholders based on their level of &lt;em&gt;power&lt;/em&gt; (ability to influence outcomes) and &lt;em&gt;interest&lt;/em&gt; (degree of concern or engagement with the initiative).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VUCA: Navigating Volatility, Uncertainty, Complexity, and Ambiguity</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vuca/</link><pubDate>Fri, 31 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vuca/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Originally coined by the U.S. Army War College in the late 1980s, &lt;em&gt;VUCA&lt;/em&gt; describes the conditions of Volatility, Uncertainty, Complexity, and Ambiguity that characterize the modern operating environment. It has since become a foundational concept in strategy, leadership, and organizational design to understand why traditional linear planning fails in dynamic contexts.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How Purpose Create Economic Resilience</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/29/purpose-economic-resilience/</link><pubDate>Wed, 29 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/29/purpose-economic-resilience/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Periods of crisis often expose the limits of efficiency-based economics. While lean operations and financial optimization maximize short-term performance, they leave systems vulnerable to disruption. The past decade has shown that stability depends as much on capital and technology as on &lt;em&gt;trust, coherence, and shared purpose&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Decision to Impact: The Strategic Role of Technical Judgement</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/28/technical-decision-making-strategy/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/28/technical-decision-making-strategy/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In contemporary organizations, technology has become a strategic determinant of competitiveness, adaptability, and value creation. As such, every technical decision carries implications that extend beyond engineering performance into business continuity, scalability, and long-term sustainability.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Strategic Coherence: Managing Scope, Expectations, and Stakeholders</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/28/strategic-coherence/</link><pubDate>Tue, 28 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2025/10/28/strategic-coherence/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In complex organizational environments, the success of any project depends less on technical precision than on alignment between strategy and execution, expectations and capacity, and among diverse stakeholder interests. This misalignment often arises from fragmented communication, conflicting incentives, or a lack of shared understanding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Dynamic Capabilities: Building Organizational Agility and Strategic Renewal</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/dynamic-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/dynamic-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-changing environments, traditional sources of competitive advantage, such as proprietary technology or market share, erode quickly. To remain resilient and relevant, organizations need to cultivate what we call &lt;em&gt;Dynamic Capabilities&lt;/em&gt; — the capacity to integrate, build, and reconfigure internal and external resources to address shifting opportunities and threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Porter's Five Forces: Assessing Competitive Structure and Market Attractiveness</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/porters-five-forces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/porters-five-forces/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic planning requires insight into the competitive dynamics that define an organization&amp;rsquo;s external reality.
Michael Porter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Five Forces Framework&lt;/em&gt; remains one of the most rigorous models for assessing industry structure, competitive pressure, and long-term profitability potential.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SWOT Analysis: From Diagnostic Framework to Strategic Synthesis</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/swot-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/swot-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;em&gt;SWOT Analysis&lt;/em&gt; remains one of the most enduring and widely used frameworks to understand where the organization stands, both in relation to itself and to its environment. Originally designed as a diagnostic tool, SWOT (Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, Threats) enables organizations to integrate &lt;em&gt;internal capabilities&lt;/em&gt; with &lt;em&gt;external conditions&lt;/em&gt; into a clear picture of strategic fit. However, the true value of the model lies in transforming these factors into &lt;em&gt;strategic imperatives&lt;/em&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VRIO Framework: Assessing Internal Resources for Sustainable Advantage</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vrio-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vrio-framework/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding competitive advantage requires examining the &lt;em&gt;resources and capabilities&lt;/em&gt; that allow an organization to perform better than its rivals. The &lt;em&gt;VRIO Framework&lt;/em&gt; provides a structured method to evaluate which assets and competencies can create enduring strategic advantage rather than temporary success.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ESTEMPLE* Analysis: A Comprehensive Framework for Environmental Scanning</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/estemple-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/estemple-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every strategic plan begins with a simple question: &lt;em&gt;In what environment does the organization operate, and how might that environment evolve?&lt;/em&gt; Traditional environmental analysis often relies on &lt;em&gt;PESTEL&lt;/em&gt; (Political, Economic, Social, Technological, Environmental, and Legal factors). However, the complexity of today&amp;rsquo;s ecosystems requires a broader, more systemic perspective. The &lt;em&gt;ESTEMPLE* framework&lt;/em&gt; extends this logic by adding &lt;em&gt;Media&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;Ethics&lt;/em&gt;, and other relevant factors, offering a richer lens through which to evaluate the macro-environmental forces shaping the organization&amp;rsquo;s trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Introduction to Security and Compliance</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/introduction-security-compliance/</link><pubDate>Thu, 24 Jul 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/introduction-security-compliance/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Realign your business strategically</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/align-with-core-competencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/align-with-core-competencies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Designing a Strategic Plan</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/strategic-plan/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 May 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/strategic-plan/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Agility with Purpose: Building Adaptable Organizations</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2023/12/17/agility-with-purpose/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2023/12/17/agility-with-purpose/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an environment characterized by volatility, uncertainty, complexity, and ambiguity (&lt;a href="https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vuca/"&gt;VUCA&lt;/a&gt;), organizational survival depends on adaptability. Yet agility, often reduced to a set of project management rituals, is not synonymous with flexibility alone. True agility lies in the organization&amp;rsquo;s ability to learn, reprioritize, and execute while maintaining coherence with its strategic intent.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Competing Beyond Price: Value, Positioning, and Sustainable Advantage</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2023/10/16/competing-beyond-price/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2023/10/16/competing-beyond-price/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In increasingly saturated markets, many firms default to price competition as the most immediate route to market share. However, price-based rivalry is inherently unsustainable: it erodes margins, diminishes perceived value, and initiates a self-reinforcing cycle of commoditization.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Strategy in Motion: Sustainability, Innovation, and Dynamic Capability</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2022/07/15/sustainability-innovation/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Jul 2022 00:00:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2022/07/15/sustainability-innovation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In an environment defined by accelerating technological change, resource constraints, and stakeholder scrutiny, strategic advantage increasingly depends on adaptability. Static strategies anchored in long-term forecasts are no longer sufficient. Organizations need to cultivate &lt;a href="https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/dynamic-capabilities/"&gt;&lt;em&gt;dynamic capabilities&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/a&gt;: the ability to integrate, build, and reconfigure competencies in response to shifting conditions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Defining the Social Entrepreneur: Motivation, Behaviour, and Impact</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The concept of social entrepreneurship has expanded considerably over the past two decades, yet its definition remains unclear. This ambiguity can undermine the credibility of social entrepreneurs, weaken institutional support, and complicate impact measurement. Establishing a shared understanding is therefore essential for distinguishing social entrepreneurship from both traditional business and philanthropy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Winning on Simplicity: Aldi's Dual Strategy of Cost Leadership and Quality Differentiation</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/aldi-strategic-case-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 22 Jun 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/aldi-strategic-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the years, Aldi blazed the trail for the hard-discounters within the US grocery retail industry. The firm&amp;rsquo;s current obsession with product quality, combined with its focus on low prices (Ramaswamy, 2020), suggests that winning for the company means offering &lt;strong&gt;the best quality at the lowest price&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Purpose Meets Profit: Insights from Emerging Social Entrepreneurs in Toronto</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social entrepreneurship has emerged as a distinctive response to complex social and environmental challenges that traditional business and public institutions have failed to address effectively. By combining entrepreneurial methods with social purpose, these ventures aim to create value that extends beyond financial profit. Yet, despite growing academic and policy interest, the lived experiences of social entrepreneurs, and the factors that shape their motivations, behaviours, and constraints, remain insufficiently understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>From Retail to the Cloud: Strategic Reinvention and Competitive Advantage at Amazon</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/amazon-strategic-case-study/</link><pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/amazon-strategic-case-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Amazon&amp;rsquo;s evolution from an online bookstore into a global technology ecosystem represents one of the most remarkable strategic transformations in modern business history. Founded in 1994 by Jeff Bezos, the company has expanded across e-commerce, logistics, entertainment, cloud computing, and artificial intelligence. Today, it dominates multiple industries simultaneously, driven by a culture of innovation, customer obsession, and data-centric decision-making.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Balancing Profit and Preservation: Sustainable Strategies for Wildlife Management in South Africa</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kruger National Park is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most biodiverse conservation areas, renowned for its ecological management practices and anti-poaching operations. It attracts millions of visitors each year, contributing significantly to South Africa&amp;rsquo;s tourism economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>