<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Experience on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/</link><description>Recent content in My Experience on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>© 2024 Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Executive Advisor, Business &amp; Technology</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2024-01-executive-advisor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2024-01-executive-advisor/</guid><description>Empowering tech company leaders to achieve sustainable business growth through personalised advice and targeted training.</description></item><item><title>Business Insights Host</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2021-01-business-insights-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2021-01-business-insights-host/</guid><description>Launched a series of discussions aimed at sharing insights into business, entrepreneurship, and promoting social entrepreneurs.
• Leveraged personal business knowledge and experience alongside guest entrepreneurs to produce high-quality content.</description></item><item><title>Social Entrepreneur</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2021-02-social-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2021-02-social-entrepreneur/</guid><description>Time for a Change is the first collaborative environmental literacy platform.
Its mission is to provide people with reliable, comprehensive information, empowering them to understand environmental issues fully and take informed action as responsible citizens and economic agents.</description></item><item><title>Business Advisor</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2020-02-business-advisor-schulich/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2020-02-business-advisor-schulich/</guid><description>Collaborated with a social enterprise to develop and implement a robust marketing strategy and business plan aimed at identifying its target market and establishing momentum for growth.
Achievements
• Identified a pertinent target segment and crafted a positioning strategy that significantly enhanced customer engagement and market penetration.</description></item><item><title>Business Advisor</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2019-09-business-advisor-otago/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2019-09-business-advisor-otago/</guid><description>Helped an SME capitalise on regulatory challenges surrounding GHG emissions (NZETS), transforming them into opportunities for clients, including farmers and corporations.
Achievements
• Developed a strategic plan introducing an innovative solution that utilised farmer-corporation relationships to effectively offset GHG emissions while also creating positive impacts within local communities.</description></item><item><title>Senior Technical Program &amp; Delivery Manager</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2017-11-senior-tpm-tdm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2017-11-senior-tpm-tdm/</guid><description>Led the international scaling of the engineering team for a French startup, maintaining high-quality standards and enabling effective collaboration among distributed teams.
Achievements
• Collaborated with product leadership and company executives to define OKRs and strategic plans, aligning team efforts with organisational objectives.</description></item><item><title>Head of Engineering</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2017-07-head-of-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2017-07-head-of-engineering/</guid><description>Led the transformation of a SaaS firm&amp;rsquo;s cloud platform, pivotal in executing the company&amp;rsquo;s strategic expansion into European markets.
Achievements
• Doubled the team&amp;rsquo;s long-term velocity while maintaining high quality through comprehensive team support, fostering knowledge sharing, addressing functional and technical bottlenecks, and promoting an Agile and engaged mindset.</description></item><item><title>Senior Business &amp; Tech Consultant, Auditor</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-09-tech-consultant-and-auditor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-09-tech-consultant-and-auditor/</guid><description>As a consultant specialising in high-growth tech companies, I provided strategic guidance to address operational, technical, and organisational challenges. My approach involved immersing myself in daily operations and engaging with stakeholders across departments to gain a holistic understanding of each organisation&amp;rsquo;s needs.</description></item><item><title>Founder, Business &amp; Technology Leader</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-09-crafties-founder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-09-crafties-founder/</guid><description>Recognising unmet needs in the tech industry, I transitioned to self-employment to explore and validate market opportunities. After a year of successful exploration, I founded Crafties to address these gaps and develop innovative solutions.</description></item><item><title>Tech Community Leader</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-06-creator-and-leader-kotlin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-06-creator-and-leader-kotlin/</guid><description>Established and led the Kotlin Lyon community in France, dedicated to learning and sharing insights on the Kotlin programming language.
• Created partnerships with local companies to host community events, fostering networking and educational opportunities.</description></item><item><title>Software Practices Advocate</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-04-crafties-channel-creator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2016-04-crafties-channel-creator/</guid><description>Created and managed the Crafties YouTube channel focused on sharing insights and best practices in software engineering: https://www.youtube.com/Crafties
• Produced and published informative content to engage with the software engineering community.</description></item><item><title>SaaS Entrepreneur</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2015-07-saas-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2015-07-saas-entrepreneur/</guid><description>Developed a cloud-based invoice management platform to support Honduran entrepreneurs in navigating recent legislative changes affecting their businesses.
Achievements
• Engineered and launched a user-friendly platform that simplifies compliance with complex legislative requirements, including invoice numeration, format specifications, required information, and handling marginal cases.</description></item><item><title>Technical Program Manager</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2014-04-tpm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2014-04-tpm/</guid><description>Led pivotal initiatives for the nationwide Linky project in France as part of a team of over 100 people dedicated to replacing standard electricity meters with advanced, remotely operated systems.</description></item><item><title>Team Lead</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2013-02-team-lead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2013-02-team-lead/</guid><description>Led the qualification of a critical BioMérieux software project, pivotal in validating and releasing medical reagent batches at the end of the production chain.
Achievements
• Ensured that differences between the new and old software&amp;rsquo;s calculations were not statistically significant, achieving compliance with regulatory standards and operational requirements.</description></item><item><title>Biotechnology Engineer</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2012-02-biotechnology-engineer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2012-02-biotechnology-engineer/</guid><description>Led a high-stakes project at Sanofi Pasteur focused on optimising measurement parameters for critical equipment, achieving significant advancements in operational efficiency and reliability.
Achievements
• Implemented and executed a successful optimisation strategy within a few weeks, resolving a persistent challenge that had eluded previous attempts for over 7 years.</description></item><item><title>Social Project Leader</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2003-09-social-project-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/experience/2003-09-social-project-leader/</guid><description>Directed a transformative social project in Honduras to renovate a school, emphasising community engagement and sustainable development.
Achievements
• Orchestrated the construction of multiple new classrooms, significantly enhancing educational infrastructure and opportunities.</description></item></channel></rss>