<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>My Experience on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/</link><description>Recent content in My Experience on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>© 2025 Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/experience/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Business Insights Host</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2021-01-business-insights-host/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2021-01-business-insights-host/</guid><description>&lt;p>Launched a discussion series to share insights on business and entrepreneurship and promote social entrepreneurs.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Leveraged my business expertise and collaborated with guest entrepreneurs to create high-quality content.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Amplified guest visibility across multiple channels through strategic content distribution and promotion.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Entrepreneur</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2021-02-social-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Jan 2021 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2021-02-social-entrepreneur/</guid><description>&lt;p>Launched the first collaborative environmental literacy platform, leveraging collective knowledge to address our environmental crisis.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Its mission is to provide reliable, comprehensive information that enables individuals to understand environmental issues in depth and make informed decisions as responsible citizens and economic agents.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Executive Advisor, Business &amp; Technology</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2019-09-executive-advisor/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Sep 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2019-09-executive-advisor/</guid><description>&lt;p>Turning complexity into strategic opportunities, enabling sustainable growth, and empowering tech leaders to innovate, scale, and lead change through executive advisory, Agile practices, and high-impact self-paced training.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior Technical Program &amp; Delivery Manager</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2017-11-senior-tpm-tdm/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Nov 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2017-11-senior-tpm-tdm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Scaled a French startup&amp;rsquo;s engineering team internationally, ensuring high-quality standards and fostering effective collaboration across distributed teams.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Collaborated with product leadership and company executives to define OKRs and strategic plans, aligning team efforts with organizational objectives.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Head of Engineering</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2017-07-head-of-engineering/</link><pubDate>Sat, 01 Jul 2017 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2017-07-head-of-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;p>Transformed a SaaS company’s cloud platform to enable European market expansion, spearheading a seamless legacy system migration that accelerated time-to-market and fueled business growth.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Doubled the team’s long-term velocity while maintaining high quality by providing comprehensive support, fostering knowledge sharing, resolving functional and technical bottlenecks, and cultivating an Agile, engaged mindset.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Senior Business &amp; Tech Consultant, Auditor</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-09-tech-consultant-and-auditor/</link><pubDate>Fri, 02 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-09-tech-consultant-and-auditor/</guid><description>&lt;p>As a consultant specializing in high-growth tech companies, I provided strategic guidance to overcome operational, technical, and organizational challenges. My approach involved immersing myself in daily operations and collaborating with stakeholders across departments to deeply understand each organization’s unique needs.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Founder, Business &amp; Technology Leader</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-09-crafties-founder/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-09-crafties-founder/</guid><description>&lt;p>Recognizing unmet needs in the tech industry, I transitioned to self-employment to explore and validate market opportunities. Within months of successful exploration, I founded Crafties to close these gaps with innovative solutions.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Tech Community Leader</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-06-creator-and-leader-kotlin/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jun 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-06-creator-and-leader-kotlin/</guid><description>&lt;p>Founded and led the Kotlin Lyon community in France, focused on learning and sharing insights about the Kotlin programming language.&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Built partnerships with local companies to host events, fostering networking and skill-building opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Software Practices Advocate</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-04-crafties-channel-creator/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2016 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2016-04-crafties-channel-creator/</guid><description>&lt;p>Created and managed the Crafties YouTube channel, focused on sharing insights and best practices in software engineering: &lt;a href="https://www.youtube.com/Crafties">https://www.youtube.com/Crafties&lt;/a>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Produced and published engaging, informative content for the software engineering community.&lt;/p>
&lt;/li>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Developed strategies to grow the subscriber base and increase channel visibility.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>SaaS Entrepreneur</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2015-07-saas-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Jul 2015 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2015-07-saas-entrepreneur/</guid><description>&lt;p>Developed a cloud-based invoice management platform to support Honduran entrepreneurs in navigating legislative changes, preventing business closures and fines due to limited resources.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Designed and launched an intuitive platform that simplifies compliance with complex legal requirements, including invoice numeration, format specifications, mandatory information, and handling of edge cases.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Technical Program Manager</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2014-04-tpm/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2014 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2014-04-tpm/</guid><description>&lt;p>Orchestrated key initiatives for France’s nationwide Linky project, collaborating with a team of over 100 cross-functional stakeholders to deploy millions of smart electricity meters across multiple regions.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Drove continuous value delivery by strengthening collaboration within the engineering unit—including managers, architects, and developers—while ensuring alignment with leadership and product teams.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biotechnology &amp; Software Engineering Lead</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2013-02-biotech-software-eng-lead/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Feb 2013 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2013-02-biotech-software-eng-lead/</guid><description>&lt;p>Directed bioMérieux software delivery for critical medical reagent batch release, bridging biotechnology with software engineering expertise to guarantee reliability.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Fostered multidisciplinary collaboration to streamline decisions and ensure safe, on-time deployment to production while minimizing costs and risks.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Biotechnology Engineering Consultant</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2012-02-biotechnology-consultant/</link><pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2012 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2012-02-biotechnology-consultant/</guid><description>&lt;p>Solved a 7-year-old challenge in a pivotal Sanofi Pasteur project by leading the optimization of critical equipment measurement parameters.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Delivered substantial gains in operational reliability within weeks by implementing a targeted optimization strategy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Social Project Leader</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2003-09-social-project-leader/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2003 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/experience/2003-09-social-project-leader/</guid><description>&lt;p>Directed a transformative social project in Honduras to renovate a school, emphasizing community engagement and sustainable development.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;strong>Achievements&lt;/strong>&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>
&lt;p>• Orchestrated the construction of multiple new classrooms, significantly enhancing educational infrastructure and learning opportunities.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>