<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organizational Change on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/topics/organizational-change/</link><description>Recent content in Organizational Change on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/topics/organizational-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bolman &amp; Deal's Four Frames: Decoding Organizational Dynamics</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bolman-deal-four-frames/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bolman-deal-four-frames/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizational transformations fail because leaders interpret reality through a single lens, typically structural or procedural, while neglecting the complex social, political, and symbolic dimensions that also govern collective behaviour. Bolman and Deal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Four Frames Model&lt;/strong&gt; offers a multidimensional perspective for analyzing and leading change. It invites leaders to &amp;ldquo;reframe&amp;rdquo; organizations by viewing them simultaneously as structures, communities, political arenas, and cultural systems.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bridges' Transition Model: Managing the Human Side of Change</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bridges-transition-model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bridges-transition-model/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizational transformations often focus on external structures, systems, processes, and policies, while overlooking the psychological transition that individuals experience in parallel. This neglect explains why many technically well-designed change initiatives fail to take hold: while the &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; may be implemented, the &lt;em&gt;transition&lt;/em&gt; remains incomplete. William Bridges&amp;rsquo; &lt;em&gt;Transition Model&lt;/em&gt; distinguishes between these two dimensions and provides a framework for managing the inner, human journey that enables change to endure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Force Field Analysis: Understanding the Dynamics of Organizational Change</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/force-field-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/force-field-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every organization, the current state persists because opposing forces hold it in balance. Some push in favour of transformation, while others act (sometimes invisibly) to preserve existing structures and behaviours. This tension explains why, despite clear strategic intent, change so often encounters inertia. Kurt Lewin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Force Field Analysis&lt;/em&gt; provides a conceptual and visual framework for diagnosing this equilibrium and determining where to intervene to enable progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Beckhard &amp; Harris Change Equation: Assessing the Conditions for Transformation</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/beckhard-harris-change-equation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/beckhard-harris-change-equation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many transformation efforts never gain traction because the underlying conditions for change aren&amp;rsquo;t yet strong enough to overcome organizational resistance. Beckhard and Harris&amp;rsquo;s &lt;em&gt;Change Equation&lt;/em&gt; offers a simple way to assess whether an initiative is ready to move forward. It shows that lasting transformation depends on the combined strength of dissatisfaction, vision, and first steps, and that if any one of these factors is missing, resistance will prevail.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leading Sustainable Organizational Change</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/managing-change/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/managing-change/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Realign your business strategically</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/align-with-core-competencies/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 May 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/trainings/align-with-core-competencies/</guid><description/></item><item><title>Making Change Last: Managing Organisational Transitions</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:48:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/essays/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change is an inherent feature of (organizational) life. Market disruptions, technological evolution, and shifts in workforce expectations compel companies to adapt continuously. Yet while change is ubiquitous, sustained transformation remains rare. Many initiatives succeed operationally but fail behaviourally as the structures evolve, but the people do not.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Leading Through Transition: Evaluating Engineering Transformation in a Scaling Organization</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XYZ is a tech company that offers services through an online platform where contractors can upload their legal documents. The enterprise is transitioning from a small start-up to an SME, reporting double-digit growth over the past six years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reframing Culture and Collaboration: Microsoft's Transformation Under Satya Nadella</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-paced industries such as technology, change is an ongoing necessity. Market dynamics evolve rapidly, innovation cycles shorten, and emerging competitors continuously redefine industry standards. In this environment, organizations must adapt faster than the technologies they create. Microsoft, once a dominant force in personal computing, found itself constrained by internal silos, outdated hierarchies, and a culture that incentivized competition over collaboration. As the industry shifted toward cloud computing and artificial intelligence, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s traditional model no longer aligned with market realities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>