<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Organizational Change on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/topics/organizational-change/</link><description>Recent content in Organizational Change on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/topics/organizational-change/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Leading Through Transition: Evaluating Engineering Transformation in a Scaling Organization</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</link><pubDate>Thu, 13 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/transformation-assessment/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;XYZ is a tech company that offers services through an online platform where contractors can upload their legal documents. The enterprise is transitioning from a small start-up to an SME, reporting double-digit growth over the past six years.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reframing Culture and Collaboration: Microsoft's Transformation Under Satya Nadella</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</link><pubDate>Sun, 02 Jun 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/microsoft-change-management/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-paced industries such as technology, change is an ongoing necessity. Market dynamics evolve rapidly, innovation cycles shorten, and emerging competitors continuously redefine industry standards. In this environment, organizations must adapt faster than the technologies they create. Microsoft, once a dominant force in personal computing, found itself constrained by internal silos, outdated hierarchies, and a culture that incentivized competition over collaboration. As the industry shifted toward cloud computing and artificial intelligence, Microsoft&amp;rsquo;s traditional model no longer aligned with market realities.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>