<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/categories/business/</link><description>Recent content in Business on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>© 2025 Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:48:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Effect Long-Lasting Organizational Changes</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/blog/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:48:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/blog/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Change is hard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Sometimes it&amp;rsquo;s unavoidable in life and organizations.
Take remote work: not long ago, many companies dismissed it outright. Today, they are drafting work-from-home policies they never thought they would need.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Change will happen with or without us. The real question is: what makes it last?&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>What is a Social Entrepreneur?</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/blog/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/blog/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Today, social entrepreneurship is defined in many ways. This ambiguity can blur the identity of social entrepreneurs, undermine their credibility, weaken the relevance of the guidance they receive, and ultimately hinder their impact. That is why a shared definition is essential.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This article presents my perspective and insights on social entrepreneurs, based on primary research conducted with a small random sample in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Debt and SMEs in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/debt-sme-nz/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;In this video, I dive into debt funding for small to medium businesses in New Zealand.
While headlines often talk about how “cheap” money is, especially for homeowners, the reality for SMEs is quite different.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I explore what current lending conditions mean for small businesses and share recommendations to help improve access to funding.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Cloudy Relationship Between France and Diesel</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After WWII, Charles de Gaulle jumpstarted the French economy by cutting diesel taxes for the first time, supporting haulers, farmers, and artisans who relied on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in 1980, Toyota and its revolutionary production model flooded the French market with economical and reliable cars. At the same time, France replaced all its diesel-based power plants with nuclear ones to ensure energy independence. The French government also introduced new diesel incentives to boost the competitive advantage of local manufacturers specializing in diesel engines and to dispose of the million litres of now-useless diesel from power plants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>