<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Business on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/categories/business/</link><description>Recent content in Business on Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><copyright>© 2025 Nadia Humbert-Labeaumaz</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:48:00 +0600</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nphumbert.github.io/categories/business/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>How to Effect Long-Lasting Organizational Changes</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Apr 2021 19:48:00 +0600</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2021/04/28/effecting-long-lasting-changes/</guid><description>&lt;p>Change is hard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>But sometimes, it’s simply unavoidable — in life and in organizations.
Take remote work: not long ago, many companies dismissed it entirely. Today, they’re drafting work-from-home policies they never imagined needing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Change will happen — with or without us. But what turns it into lasting success?&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>What is a Social Entrepreneur?</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</link><pubDate>Thu, 14 Jan 2021 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2021/01/14/what-is-a-social-entrepreneur/</guid><description>&lt;p>Today, social entrepreneurship is defined in many ways — an ambiguity that can blur social entrepreneurs’ identity, undermine their credibility, weaken the relevance of the guidance they receive, and ultimately hinder their impact. That’s why a shared definition is essential.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This article shares my perspective and insights into social entrepreneurs, drawn from primary research conducted on a small random sample in Toronto, Canada.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Debt and SMEs in New Zealand</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2020/07/05/debt-sme-nz/</link><pubDate>Sun, 05 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2020/07/05/debt-sme-nz/</guid><description>&lt;p>In this video, I dive into debt funding for small to medium businesses in New Zealand.
While the headlines often talk about how “cheap” money is — especially for homeowners — the reality for SMEs is quite different.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I’ll explore what current lending conditions mean for small businesses and share recommendations to help improve access to funding.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Cloudy Relationship Between France and Diesel</title><link>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2019/06/27/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nphumbert.github.io/blog/2019/06/27/cloudy-relationship-france-diesel/</guid><description>&lt;p>After WWII, Charles de Gaulle jumpstarted the French economy by cutting diesel taxes for the first time — supporting the hauliers, farmers, and artisans who relied on it.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>