<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Briefs on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/</link><description>Recent content in Briefs on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/briefs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Dynamic Capabilities: Building Organizational Agility and Strategic Renewal</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/dynamic-capabilities/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/dynamic-capabilities/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In fast-changing environments, traditional sources of competitive advantage, such as proprietary technology or market share, erode quickly. To remain resilient and relevant, organizations must cultivate what we call &lt;strong&gt;Dynamic Capabilities&lt;/strong&gt;: the capacity to &lt;strong&gt;integrate, build, and reconfigure&lt;/strong&gt; internal and external resources to address shifting opportunities and threats.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Porter's Five Forces: Assessing Competitive Structure and Market Attractiveness</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/porters-five-forces/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/porters-five-forces/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Strategic planning requires insight into the competitive dynamics that define its external reality.
Michael Porter&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Five Forces Framework&lt;/strong&gt;, remains one of the most rigorous models for assessing &lt;strong&gt;industry structure&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;competitive pressure&lt;/strong&gt;, and &lt;strong&gt;long-term profitability potential&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>SWOT Analysis: From Diagnostic Framework to Strategic Synthesis</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/swot-analysis/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/swot-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The &lt;strong&gt;SWOT Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; remains one of the most enduring and widely used frameworks to understand where the organization stands, both in relation to itself and to its environment. Originally designed as a diagnostic tool, SWOT (Strengths, Weaknesses, Opportunities, Threats) enables organizations to integrate &lt;strong&gt;internal capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; with &lt;strong&gt;external conditions&lt;/strong&gt;, creating a clear picture of strategic fit. However, the true value of the model lies in transforming these factors into &lt;strong&gt;strategic imperatives&lt;/strong&gt;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>VRIO Framework: Assessing Internal Resources for Sustainable Advantage</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vrio-framework/</link><pubDate>Sat, 25 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/vrio-framework/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Understanding competitive advantage requires looking to the &lt;strong&gt;resources and capabilities&lt;/strong&gt; that allow an organization to perform better than its rivals. The &lt;strong&gt;VRIO Framework&lt;/strong&gt; provides a structured method to evaluate which assets and competencies can create &lt;strong&gt;enduring strategic advantage&lt;/strong&gt; rather than temporary success.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>ESTEMPLE* Analysis: A Comprehensive Framework for Environmental Scanning</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/estemple-analysis/</link><pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/strategic-management/estemple-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every strategic plan begins with a simple question: &lt;em&gt;In what environment does the organization operate, and how might that environment evolve?&lt;/em&gt; Traditional environmental analysis often relies on &lt;strong&gt;PESTEL&lt;/strong&gt; (Political, Economic, Social, Technological, Environmental, and Legal factors). However, the complexity of today&amp;rsquo;s ecosystems requires a broader, more systemic perspective. The &lt;em&gt;&lt;em&gt;ESTEMPLE&lt;/em&gt; model&lt;/em&gt;* extends this logic by adding &lt;strong&gt;Media&lt;/strong&gt;, &lt;strong&gt;Ethics&lt;/strong&gt;, and other relevant factors, producing a richer lens through which to evaluate the macro-environmental forces shaping the organization&amp;rsquo;s trajectory.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bolman &amp; Deal's Four Frames: Decoding Organizational Dynamics</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bolman-deal-four-frames/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bolman-deal-four-frames/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many organizational transformations fail because leaders interpret reality through a single lens, typically structural or procedural, while neglecting the complex social, political, and symbolic dimensions that also govern collective behaviour. Bolman and Deal&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Four Frames Model&lt;/strong&gt; offers a multidimensional perspective for analyzing and leading change. It invites leaders to &amp;ldquo;reframe&amp;rdquo; the organization by viewing it simultaneously as a structure, a community, a political arena, and a cultural system.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bridges' Transition Model: Managing the Human Side of Change</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bridges-transition-model/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/bridges-transition-model/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Organizational transformations often focus on external structures, systems, processes, and policies, while overlooking the &lt;strong&gt;psychological transition&lt;/strong&gt; that individuals experience in parallel. This neglect explains why many technically well-designed change initiatives fail to take hold: while the &lt;em&gt;change&lt;/em&gt; may be implemented, the &lt;em&gt;transition&lt;/em&gt; remains incomplete. William Bridges&amp;rsquo; &lt;strong&gt;Transition Model&lt;/strong&gt; distinguishes between these two dimensions and provides a framework for managing the inner, human journey that enables change to endure.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Force Field Analysis: Understanding the Dynamics of Organizational Change</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/force-field-analysis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/force-field-analysis/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In every organization, the current state persists because opposing forces hold it in balance. Some push in favour of transformation, while others act (sometimes invisibly) to preserve existing structures and behaviours. This tension explains why, despite clear strategic intent, change so often encounters inertia. Kurt Lewin&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Force Field Analysis&lt;/strong&gt; provides a conceptual and visual framework for diagnosing this equilibrium and determining where to intervene to enable progress.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Beckhard &amp; Harris Change Equation: Assessing the Conditions for Transformation</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/beckhard-harris-change-equation/</link><pubDate>Thu, 23 Oct 2025 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/briefs/organizational-change/beckhard-harris-change-equation/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many transformation efforts don&amp;rsquo;t even begin because the underlying conditions for change are not yet strong enough to overcome organizational resistance. Beckhard and Harris&amp;rsquo;s &lt;strong&gt;Change Equation&lt;/strong&gt; offers a simple way to assess whether an initiative is ready to take place. It highlights that lasting transformation depends on the combined strength of dissatisfaction, vision, and first steps, and that if any one of these is missing, resistance will prevail.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>