<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Economics on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/tags/economics/</link><description>Recent content in Economics on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 19:03:24 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/tags/economics/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Unpacking the Housing Affordability Crisis: Structural Drivers and Policy Pathways in New Zealand</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</link><pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/housing-affordability-crisis-nz/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Since 1990, successive housing booms have pushed New Zealand property prices to levels increasingly out of reach for many aspiring first-time buyers. While existing homeowners have benefited from rising equity, newcomers face a market where the cost of ownership absorbs a disproportionate share of household income. In economic terms, this violates the equimarginal principle, which states that rational agents allocate their limited resources across different needs to maximize overall satisfaction. When housing consumes nearly all disposable income, individuals can no longer balance spending efficiently across other essential goods and services, making homeownership economically unsustainable for many Kiwis.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Incentives, Externalities, and Unintended Consequences: France's Long Dependence on Diesel</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</link><pubDate>Thu, 27 Jun 2019 19:03:24 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/diesel-incentive-france/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;After WWII, Charles de Gaulle jump-started the French economy by cutting diesel taxes for the first time, supporting haulers, farmers, and artisans who relied on it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Later, in 1980, Toyota and its revolutionary production model flooded the French market with economical and reliable cars. At the same time, France replaced all its diesel-based power plants with nuclear ones to ensure energy independence. The French government then introduced new diesel incentives to boost the competitive advantage of local manufacturers specializing in diesel engines and to dispose of the million litres of now-useless diesel from power plants.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>