<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Sustainability on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/tags/sustainability/</link><description>Recent content in Sustainability on Nadia Z. Humbert-Labeaumaz</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-US</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://nadiahl.com/tags/sustainability/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Purpose Meets Profit: Insights from Emerging Social Entrepreneurs in Toronto</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</link><pubDate>Mon, 10 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/social-entrepreneurship-study/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Social entrepreneurship has emerged as a distinctive response to complex social and environmental challenges that traditional business and public institutions have failed to address effectively. By combining entrepreneurial methods with social purpose, these ventures aim to create value that extends beyond financial profit. Yet, despite growing academic and policy interest, the lived experiences of social entrepreneurs, and the factors that shape their motivations, behaviours, and constraints, remain insufficiently understood.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Balancing Profit and Preservation: Sustainable Strategies for Wildlife Management in South Africa</title><link>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0200</pubDate><guid>https://nadiahl.com/research/sustainable-south-africa/</guid><description>&lt;h2 id="introduction"&gt;Introduction&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Kruger National Park is one of the world&amp;rsquo;s largest and most biodiverse conservation areas, renowned for its ecological management practices and anti-poaching operations. It attracts millions of visitors each year, contributing significantly to South Africa&amp;rsquo;s tourism economy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>